HARSHA PRAJAPATI

Kadugodi, Banglore, Karnataka 560067 | 886-174-1035 | harshap744@gmail.com

https://portfolio-deploy-app.herokuapp.com

Professional Summary

Experienced System Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry and Passionate Front End Web Developer with 3.4 years of experience working in different projects of Ui development and enhancement.

I love brainstorming through difficult problems and coming up with effective solutions. Since then I have been trying out new languages, spending time in making few small web applications.

Skills

- Html5
- Css3
- Javascript

- Jquery basics
- Angular 7
- Bootstrap 4

Work History

System Engineer 09/2018 to Current

TCS - Bengaluru, Karnataka

Organisation- Rolls Royce Digital

Development Project- Front End Web Developer

I started my career with C#(ASP.Net), SQL and then moved on to Javascript specifically Angular framework.

In my project I use to design the Front End for the application, by using Javascript and other Ui technologies(kendo,Bootstrap 4).

Then I learnt Angular 7 as it was required for the project, and implemented many features like data binding using angular mat tables,

services for Api's, Dependency Injection to inject services, sharing data between components using Input output properties, Observables and Promises.

I worked in Agile methodology during this period.

System Engineer 11/2017 to 08/2018

TCS- Organization: Lafarge Holcim – Bangalore, Karnataka

- Support Project -Here for a Dispatching Cement application solved problem tickets for any bug in the application by debugging the code, giving solutions in the code or executing queries in the backend in sql
- Tools used were Visual Studio, Service Now and Sql Management

Assistant System Engineer

08/2016 to 08/2017

TCS - Organization: Intel – Bangalore, Karnataka

- Ui development I worked on the Ui development using Angular Js , Html, Css
- It was an existing application where the client had asked us to redesign it in a single page application and modify the html pages and add different functionalities to it
- Tools used were Notepad ++
- Enhancement Project Worked on Problem tickets using C# for front end in Visual studio and for backend have used Sql
- Here I worked on Change Requests given by the clients to make changes in the front end Ui or to make a new

Education

Btech Biotechnology **GITAM University** - Visakhapatnam, AP focused in Biotechnology

04/2016

Awards and Achievements

- Got the best team Award- Award for excellence in Lafarge Holcim
- Got appreciation from client for Ui development
- On Hacker Earth participated in challenges using skills in Javascript, Json, Ajax calls, html and css to complete the problem statement and have cleared it
- In college fest have won 1st position for Green Innovation event

Training and Certifications

- External Certification done in Front End Web Developer I Nanodegree in Udacity
- Digital Competencies in IEvolve for AngualrJs, Html, Css and Bootstrap
- Learner on Hacker earth, have solved problem statements on it
- Active learner on TreeHouse for learning different tracks on Front End Web Development, Intermediate C#, Full stack Javascript, APIs, responsive layouts
- Completed trainings in C# asp.Net and sql